Leonard Windle Collection of Textile Related Photographs 6750 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Leonard Windle Collection of Textile Related Photographs
1959
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Leonard Windle
6750 P
0.11 cubic feet
1 file folder and one oversize photograph
Gelatin silver print, photographs.
Photographs of Davis & Furber Machine Company executives, foremen, and machinery.
10064347
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 10, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 30, 2017
Scope and Contents
Includes portraits of Davis & Furber Machine Company executives, a photograph of a Foremen's Club outing, and photographs from the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6750 G: Leonard Windle Collection of Textile Related Graphics 6605: Davis & Furber Machine Company Records 6605/001: Davis & Furber Machine Company General Records 6605 GPN: Davis & Furber Machine Co. Glass Plate Negatives 6605 G: Davis & Furber Machine Company Graphics 6605 F: Davis & Furber Machine Company Machine Company Film 6605 OH: Davis & Furber Machine Company Oral History 6605 P: Davis & Furber Machine Company Photographs 6605 PUBS: Davis & Furber Machine Company Publications
Carding-machines; Company picnics; Cotton machinery; Exhibitions; Industrial relations; Spinning--Powered--Spinning frame; Textile machinery; Textile machinery industry; Textile workers; Woolen and worsted machinery; Greenville (S.C.); North Andover (Mass.); Davis, James Henry; Gilbert, George Henry; Gleason, Benjamin Whitney; American Textile Machinery Association.; American Textile Machinery Exhibition--International; Davis & Furber Machine Co.
10064347
- Early Executives and 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibit (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: James Henry Davis, Davis & Furber Machine Company, 1908; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Halftone. Image depicts Davis (1846-1886), a partner in Davis & Furber Machine Co. beginning in 1868. Davis is seen from the chest up, wearing a dark jacket buttoned up over a white shirt and dark tie. He has a very full beard. Davis was the son of George Lucien Davis and the brother of George Gilbert Davis, all associated with Davis & Furber Machine Co. in North Andover, Mass. James Henry Davis succeeded his brother as superintendent of the card clothing dept. at Davis & Furber in 1880. This image is reproduced in "The Davis & Furber Machine Co. and the men who made it," published in 1908. 9.5 x 14 cm. Copy B.
    Format: black and white photograph.
  - Item 2: Benjamin Whitney Gleason, 1908; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Halftone. Image depicts Gleason (1806-1884), an early member of what eventually became Davis & Furber Machine Co. Gleason is seen from the chest up, wearing a dark suit and vest, dark tie, and white shirt with a stickpin in the center of it. Gleason was an employee and then partner in Gilbert, Gleason & Davis, Gleason & Davis, and Gleason, Davis & Co., all precursors of Davis & Furber Machine Co., located in North Andover, Mass. This image is reproduced in "The Davis & Furber Machine Co. and the men who made it," published in 1908. 9.5 x 14 cm. Copy B.
  - Item 3: Woolen yarn spinning frames, unknown mill, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [ca. 1900-30?]. Image depicts woolen yarn spinning frames in an unknown mill. Signed in the lower left corner: "Yours truly, W.C. McLoughlin" and "Cotton Waste & Woolen yarn Spinning Frames." Photo is badly overexposed. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 4: George Henry Gilbert, early member of Davis & Furber Machine Co., 1908; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Halftone. Image depicts Gilbert (1806-1869), an early member of what eventually became Davis & Furber Machine Co. Gilbert is seen from the chest up, wearing a dark jacket with darker (velvet?) lapels, dark vest and tie, and a white shirt. Gilbert was a founder or member of Barnes, Gilbert & Co., Gilbert & Richardson, and Barnes, Gilbert & Richardson, all precursors of Davis & Furber Machine Co., located in North Andover, Mass. This image is reproduced in "The Davis & Furber Machine Co. and the men who made it," published in 1908. 9.75 x 14 cm. Copy B.
  - Item 5: Davis & Furber Type L-7 Tape Condenser, 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts the Davis & Furber Machine Company Type L-7 Tape Condenser on display at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina. The man standing in front of it is probably a D&F representative. A tape condenser is the delivery section on a card in the woolen system. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 6: Attendees talking outside Davis & Furber booth, ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts some attendees at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina, talking outside the Davis & Furber Machine Company booth. The man in the center with the glasses is probably a D&F representative; see item 5 in this folder. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 7: Attendees at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts several groups of attendees at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina, talking in front of the show displays. Banner hanging above reads: American Textile Machinery Association Offices and Information Center." 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 8: Attendees in front of Davis & Furber compact sliver card machine, ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts several men talking in front of the Davis & Furber Machine Company's compact sliver card with type G-4-B and tandem feeders, on display at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina. One man holds what looks to be raw cotton (?). 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 9: Attendees in front of Davis & Furber compact sliver card machine, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Attendees in front of Davis & Furber compact sliver card machine, Greenville, S.C. Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts four men (two shaking hands) in front of the Davis & Furber Machine Company's compact sliver card with type G-4-B and tandem feeders, on display at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina. Part of the carder is visible on the left. The man wearing glasses is probably a D&F representative; see item 5 in this folder. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 10: Three exhibitors in front of Davis & Furber compact sliver card machine, ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Three exhibitors in front of Davis & Furber compact sliver card machine, ATME-I, Greenville, S.C. Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts two women, dressed in identical uniforms including broad-brimmed hats, and one man (shaking hands with one of the women) in front of the Davis & Furber Machine Company's compact sliver card with type G-4-B and tandem feeders, on display at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina. Part of the carder is visible on the left. The women wear exhibitor badges but the company name is not legible. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 11: Four attendees in front of Davis & Furber compact sliver card machine, ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts four men chatting in front of the Davis & Furber Machine Company's compact sliver card with type G-4-B feeder, on display at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina. Machine is obscured by the men. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 12: Attendees at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 13: Attendees surrounding Davis & Furber machinery at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts attendees at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina, surrounding Davis & Furber Machine Company machinery. In the foreground is the D&F Type L-X Mixing Picker; in the background on the right is the D&F Compact Sliver card with Type G-4-B Feeder. The Davis & Furber booth is on the left. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 14: Attendees surrounding Davis & Furber carding machine at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Attendees surrounding Davis & Furber carding machine at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C. Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts attendees at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina, surrounding Davis & Furber Machine Company carding machine. Machine is obscured by the men. Banner above reads: "Cematex European Information." 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 15: Attendees at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts a group of attendees at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina, talking in front of the show displays. A carding machine (Davis & Furber's?) is on the left; other machinery visible in the background. Several men lean over the balcony on the second floor in the background. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 16: Attendees at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts several groups of attendees at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina, talking in front of the show displays. A Davis & Furber Compact Sliver Card with Type G-4-B Feeder is in the center of the room. Other machinery is visible in the background. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 17: Attendees at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts several groups of attendees at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina, talking in front of the show displays. A Davis & Furber (?) carder is somewhat visible on the left. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 18: Attendees at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., in front of the Davis & Furber tape condenser, 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Attendees at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., in front of the Davis & Furber tape condenser. Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts several men grouped in front of the new Davis & Furber Type L-7 Tape Condenser at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 19: Attendees at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts several groups of attendees in front of the machinery on exhibit at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 20: Attendees at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts several groups of attendees in front of the machinery on exhibit at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina. The Davis & Furber Compact Sliver Card with Type G-4-B Feeder is partially visible on the left. A weighing feeder full of raw cotton (?) is partially visible on the right. See item 22 in this folder for a better view of this machine. 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 21: Attendees in front of Davis & Furber Machine Company display at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts three men admiring the Davis & Furber Machine Company display panels at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina. The display panels offer off the shelf delivery of parts and supplies from North Andover (Mass.) or Charlotte (N.C.). The 12.75 x 10 cm.
  - Item 22: New Davis & Furber weighing feeder at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts a man standing in the raw cotton in the new weighing feeder by Davis & Furber Machine Company at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I), Greenville, South Carolina. The 10.5 x 12.75 cm.
  - Item 23: Attendees in front of the Davis & Furber display at the ATME-I, Greenville, S.C., 1968; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts attendees at the 1968 American Textile Machinery Exhibition - International (ATME-I) in Greenville, South Carolina, in front of the Davis & Furber Machine Company display. The 12.5 x 10.5 cm.
- Davis & Furber Foremen's Club, 1959; black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
  oversize photo
  - Item 1: Davis & Furber Machine Company Foremen's Club Outing, Amesbury, Mass., 1959; black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [1959]. Image depicts a number of men playing horseshoes in the center right foreground. Other men lean against cars parked on the right and the left. Written on reverse: "D & F Foremen's' Club Outing Amesbury, Mass. Used in D&F News July 1959." 41.5 x 18.5 cm. (w/out mount); 43.25 x 23.25 cm. (w/mount).